<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id">ca-app-pub-3940256099942544/6300978111</string>
    <string name="app_name">An Unofficial Guide To GOT</string>
    <string name="mCharacters">Lannisters</string>
    <string name="starks">Starks</string>
    <string name="grey">Greyjoy</string>
    <string name="tyrell">Tyrell</string>
    <string name="gHouses">Current Great Houses</string>
    <string name="eHouses">Exiled Great Houses</string>
    <string name="extinct">Extinct Great Houses</string>
    <string name="ArrHeader">House Arryn</string>
    <string name="Arryn">HOUSE ARRYN</string>
    <string name="BarHeader">House Baratheon</string>
    <string name="HisHeader">History</string>
    <string name="BolHeader">House Bolton</string>
    <string name="BaeHeader">House Baelish</string>
    <string name="GreyHeader">House Greyjoy</string>
    <string name="LanHeader">House Lannister</string>
    <string name="MarHeader">House Martell</string>
    <string name="TyHeader">House Tyrell</string>
    <string name="MemHeaders">Members</string>
    <string name="StaHeader">House Stark</string>
    <string name="TarHeader">House Targaryen</string>
    <string name="TullHeader">House Tully</string>
    <string name="DurHeader">House Durrandon</string>
    <string name="GarHeader">House Gardener</string>
    <string name="HoaHeader">House Hoare</string>
    <string name="AryaHeader">Arya Stark</string>
    <string name="FirstHeader">The First Men</string>
    <string name="childHeader"> The Children of the Forest</string>
    <string name="longHeader">The Long Night</string>
    <string name="andalHeader">The Andals and The Invasion </string>
    <string name="valyHeader">Valyria and The Century of Blood</string>
    <string name="TarConqHeader">The Targaryren Conquest</string>
    <string name="TarDyHeader">The Targaryen Dynasty</string>
    <string name="RobRebHeader">Roberts Rebellion</string>
    <string name="reHeader">RELIGION</string>
    <string name="peHeader">PEOPLE</string>
    <string name="cuHeader">CUSTOMS</string>
    <string name="curHeader">LANGUAGES</string>
    <string name="paHeader">PARLEY</string>
    <string name="whiteHeader">White Walkers</string>
    <string name="draHeader">Dragons</string>
    <string name="wiHeader">Wights</string>
    <string name="giantHeader">Giants</string>
    <string name="mantiHeader">Manticores</string>
    <string name="valSteelHeader">Valyrian Steel</string>
    <string name="milkHeader">Milk Of The Poppy</string>
    <string name="wildHeader">Wildfire</string>
    <string name="draGlass">Dragon Glass</string>
    <string name="weirHeader">Weirwood</string>
    <string name="stranHeader">The Strangler</string>
    <string name="otherHeader">Others</string>
    <string name="brann_stark">BRANN STARK</string>
    <string name="gendry">GENDRY</string>
    <string name="gilly">GILLY</string>
    <string name="gilly_text">"Gilly is one of the many daughters of Craster, a wildling who lives beyond the Wall. She lives with him at Craster's Keep. As well as being a daughter of Craster, she is one of his wives, as Craster routinely marries his own daughters. At the time of the War of the Five Kings, Craster has nineteen wives, including Gilly. When the Night's Watch encounters her, Gilly is pregnant with the incestuous child of her own father. "</string>
    <string name="jaime">JAIME</string>
    <string name="jaime_text">Ser Jaime Lannister is a knight of the Kingsguard, a position he has held for twenty years since he was a teenager, the youngest Kingsguard ever. He was appointed to the position by the Mad King, Aerys II Targaryen.
\n
\nAt the conclusion of Robert\'s Rebellion, Jaime\'s father Tywin betrayed King Aerys by arriving at the gates of King\'s Landing with the main Lannister army and pleading his allegiance, then after his army was allowed inside the gates, turning them loose to attack the city. As Lannister soldiers raped and pillaged throughout the city during the Sack of King\'s Landing, King Aerys remained holed up inside the Red Keep, for hours maniacally repeating the order to \'burn them all\'. Despite being sworn by the holiest oaths to protect the king as a member of the Kingsguard, Jaime ultimately turned his own sword on Aerys, slaying him at the foot of the Iron Throne itself. For this infamous act, he is known throughout the Seven Kingdoms as \'the Kingslayer\', to his irritation.
\n
\nJaime always refused to discuss precisely what happened the day he slew the Mad King, and thus his true motivations– and what Aerys nearly did to King\'s Landing– were never revealed. On one occasion he confides the truth to Brienne of Tarth: Aerys\' final orders were for Jaime to kill his father, and to burn the entire city and its inhabitants with wildfire. Unwilling to let that happen, Jaime killed him, and in doing so actually saved thousands of innocent lives. He adds that the \'honorable\' Ned Stark judged him guilty immediately, without hearing Jaime\'s reasons.
\n
\nHe was forgiven his breaking of his vows by King Robert Baratheon and permitted to remain in the Kingsguard as part of Robert\'s alliance with House Lannister, along with the marriage of Jaime\'s twin sister Cersei to Robert. In addition to the slaying of the Mad King, Jaime is known for his good looks, arrogant demeanor, and superb martial skills. He is so skilled with a sword that he claims that there are only three men in the seven kingdoms which may have a chance at beating him in a fair duel.
\n
\nJaime is the eldest son of Joanna Lannister and Lord Tywin Lannister. Tywin is the head of House Lannister, the richest man in the Seven Kingdoms and Lord Paramount of the Westerlands. The Westerlands are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Lannister is one of the Great Houses of the realm. Jaime had great difficulty learning to read as a child because he transposed letters in his mind. Tywin sat with him through four hour a day practices until he learnt. Jaime resented being forced to spend so much time on reading.
\n
\nJaime is the older brother of Tyrion and the twin brother of Cersei. Their mother died giving birth to Tyrion. Due to his place in the Kingsguard, Jaime cannot inherit his father\'s lands or titles, making Tyrion his father\'s heir; a fact which vexes Tywin. Unlike Cersei and Tywin, Jaime always treated Tyrion with a degree of kindness and respect. In a secret known to only a few, Jaime is Cersei\'s lover and the biological father of her children, Joffrey, Myrcella, and Tommen, whom the world believes are Robert\'s kin.</string>
    <string name="jeor">JEOR MORMONT</string>
    <string name="jeor_text">Jeor Mormont, nicknamed The Old Bear, is the Lord Commander of the Night\'s Watch, leading from his headquarters at the fortress of Castle Black. Jeor Mormont was once the Lord of Bear Island and head of House Mormont until he abdicated his seat in favor of his son, Ser Jorah Mormont, and joined the Night\'s Watch. He rapidly rose through the ranks to become Lord Commander. His son Jorah disgraced himself by selling slaves and fled to the Free Cities, leaving Jeor\'s sister Maege to rule Bear Island</string>
    <string name="joffrey_baratheon">JOFFREY BARATHEON</string>
    <string name="joffrey_text">Joffrey is believed to be the oldest son and heir of King Robert Baratheon and Queen Cersei Lannister, both of whom entered into a political marriage alliance after Robert took the throne by force from the Mad King Aerys II Targaryen. In reality, his father is Jaime Lannister, the queen\'s brother and the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard. He has a younger sister, Myrcella, and a younger brother, Tommen , both whom are also the product of Jaime and Cersei\'s incest. 
\n
\nJoffrey takes after his mother in terms of looks and personality, his blonde hair being a subtle clue that he isn\'t really a Baratheon, who famously always possess black hair even when one of their parents possesses blonde hair. He is usually accompanied by his sworn shield, the formidable Sandor Clegane, who is better known as the Hound. Even before he ascends to the Iron Throne, Joffrey is spoiled, arrogant, cowardly, and sadistic; however these traits are further exacerbated upon Robert\'s death and his ascension to the crown.</string>
    <string name="jon_snow">JON SNOW</string>
    <string name="jon_snow_text">Jon is the bastard son of Lord Eddard Stark of Winterfell, the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms in Westeros, and House Stark is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Stark rules the region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also holds the title Lord of Winterfell. He is also the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.
\n
\nEddard once told King Robert Baratheon that Jon\'s mother is a serving girl named Wylla, but refused to elaborate any further. Jon himself has no knowledge of his mother.
\n
\nJon was raised at Winterfell on an equal footing with Eddard\'s legitimate children. He has an older half-brother Robb, two younger half-sisters Sansa and Arya, and two younger half-brothers Bran and Rickon. Jon\'s presence at Winterfell is a source of friction between Eddard and his wife, Catelyn, although Catelyn put aside her anger temporarily when the infant Jon became severely ill. Jon got on well with his half-siblings, particularly Robb and Arya.</string>
    <string name="jorah_mormont">JORAH MORMONT</string>
    <string name="jorah_text">"Jorah Mormont is the son of Jeor Mormont of House Mormont, the Lords of Bear Island and vassals of House Stark in the North. Jorah had a distinguished early career, and participating in the Siege of Pyke during the Greyjoy Rebellion, for which he was knighted by King Robert Baratheon. His father later voluntarily joined the Night's Watch, leaving Jorah as Lord of Bear Island and head of House Mormont.
\n
\nJorah married Lynesse Hightower, but his new wife had expensive tastes which Jorah struggled to fund to make her happy. Ultimately he resorted to selling poachers into slavery, which has been illegal in the Seven Kingdoms for millennia and is a great taboo throughout Westeros. Jorah was caught and disgraced. He was stripped of his Lordship and fled to the Free Cities to avoid being executed by Eddard Stark. He served in mercenary companies such as the Golden Company. His wife eventually left him for another, richer man.
\n
\nHe is called Jorah the Andal by the Dothraki, as they apparently assume that all people from Westeros are Andals. However, Jorah is actually a Northman, descended from the First Men.
\n
\nBesides the Common Tongue of Westeros, Ser Jorah is fluent in the Dothraki language. "</string>
    <string name="khal_drogo">KHAL DROGO</string>
    <string name="khaldrogo_text">Drogo is a khal or warlord of the Dothraki, the famed nomadic horse-lords of the eastern continent beyond the Narrow Sea. The Dothraki are fierce warriors, skilled in battle, unrelenting in combat and known for savagery towards non-Dothraki. Amongst their own people they have a code of honor, albeit still a harsh and unforgiving one. Drogo was very young to have his own khalasar, particularly such a large one. He is a legendary warrior and has never been defeated in battle. Drogo desired the most beautiful and exotic woman in the world as his khaleesi or wife, and enlisted Magister Illyrio Mopatis of Pentos to help him find such a woman.
\n
\nHe is guarded by bloodriders including Qotho. Generals or ko in his khalasar include Pono and Jhaqo, men who guard him, follow him in battle and, when Drogo dies, it is their duty and honor to follow him even then to continue serving him.</string>
    <string name="margaery_tyrell">MARGAERY TYRELL</string>
    <string name="margaery_text">Margaery is the only daughter of Lady Alerie Tyrell and Lord Mace Tyrell, the Lord Paramount of the Reach. The Reach is one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Tyrell is one of the Great Houses of the realm. Margaery was raised in privilege in the family seat and regional capital of Highgarden. She is close to her brother, Ser Loras Tyrell, the Knight of Flowers. She is said to be as beautiful as she is clever.</string>
    <string name="melisandre">MELISANDRE</string>
    <string name="melisandre_text">Originally born a slave in Essos, Melisandre is a Red Priestess of the Lord of Light, a deity that is not widely worshiped in Westeros. Hailing from Asshai, a country located in the far east of the continent of Essos, she claims to wield powerful magical abilities, particularly the power of prophecy. Melisandre wears a large ruby necklace that seems to glow whenever she performs her magic. Some years ago she crossed the Narrow Sea and came to the court of Lord Stannis Baratheon on the island stronghold of Dragonstone, to preach her faith. Stannis and the majority of his household have now converted to her religion, and she has become a close adviser to Stannis himself.</string>
    <string name="petyr_baelish">PETYR BAELISH</string>
    <string name="petyr_text">"Petyr Baelish is the head of House Baelish and the lord of an extremely minor holding, so small it has neither name nor maester, located in a small area within the Fingers, a coastal region in the northeastern shores of the Vale of Arryn. In reference to his family's humble domain in the smallest of the Fingers, as well as his small size, Edmure Tully nicknamed him 'Littlefinger' when they were children and Petyr was fostered at Riverrun. The nickname would stick with him throughout his life. Eventually even Baelish sarcastically embraced the nickname, due to the fact that it demonstrated how far he had risen, from a poor minor noble from the 'little Finger' peninsula to one of the most powerful officials in the Seven Kingdoms.
\n
\nDespite Baelish's humble origins, his financial acumen has seen him rise to the small council and the rank of Master of Coin, the treasurer of the Seven Kingdoms, under King Robert Baratheon. His naked ambition often places him at odds with the Master of Whisperers Lord Varys. He is a friend of Lady Catelyn Stark, one of the few contacts she has at court. Baelish's father was a wartime friend of Catelyn's father, Lord Hoster Tully.
\n
\nHe challenged her betrothed Brandon Stark to a duel and was severely injured. Brandon was later killed by King Aerys II Targaryen but Catelyn married his younger brother Eddard Stark in his place. He owns a number of brothels in King's Landing. Though the symbol of his family is the head of the Titan of Braavos, Petyr prefers to use a personal sigil, that of an unthreatening mockingbird. "</string>
    <string name="ramsay_bolton">RAMSAY BOLTON</string>
    <string name="ramsay_text">&quot;Ramsay Snow, better known as 'The Bastard of Bolton', is Lord Roose Bolton's bastard son and only living child following the death of Domeric Bolton, as well as the only possible heir to House Bolton. He stayed behind at the Dreadfort to rule as its castellan when his father left for the south to fight in the War of the Five Kings.
\n Ramsay keeps a pack of dogs, which he employs for hunting.As the bastard son of Lord Roose Bolton, Ramsay originally used the traditional surname for bastards born in the North, and was known as 'Ramsay Snow'. However, he has recently been legitimized as Lord Roose's lawful son, and has therefore been officially renamed 'Ramsay Bolton' and thus giving him all the rights of a trueborn son.  \n
\nRamsay is violent and sadistic, and fond of the ancient Bolton practice of flaying. During the War of the Five Kings, he is dispatched by his father to retake Winterfell from Theon Greyjoy. Ramsay massacres the ironborn garrison, puts the castle to the torch, and takes Theon prisoner. He subjects Theon to extensive physical and psychological torture, turning him into a broken pet named 'Reek'. &quot;</string>
    <string name="robert_baratheon">ROBERT BARATHEON</string>
    <string name="robert_text">Robert is the first son of Steffon Baratheon and Cassana Baratheon, and has two younger brothers, Stannis and Renly. Steffon was the head of House Baratheon and Lord Paramount of the Stormlands. The Stormlands are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Baratheon is one of the Great Houses of the realm. His parents died in his youth  when their ship was caught in a storm; Robert, standing on the walls of Storm\'s End with Stannis, witnessed his parents ship that was returning from Essos break up on the rocks. He inherited the lordship, and was fostered by Jon Arryn, the head of House Arryn, another Great House. Eddard Stark, the second son of House Stark, was also fostered by Jon Arryn and Robert and Eddard became as close as brothers.
\n
\nRobert served King Aerys II Targaryen (known as the Mad King) as the Lord Paramount of the Stormlands. Robert was betrothed to Lyanna Stark, Eddard\'s sister. Lyanna was kidnapped by Prince Rhaegar Targaryen.
\n
\nThe mad king had Eddard\'s father and brother killed for protesting against the kidnapping. This sparked a massive uprising against the Mad King led by Robert, Eddard and Jon Arryn. Lyanna and Aerys died during the civil war that followed. Robert claimed the Iron Throne because he started the
\n
\nwar and killed Prince Rhaegar personally. Robert also had the best claim to the throne as a result of being related to the Targaryens of old through his mother\'s side. The other leaders of the rebels, Jon Arryn and Eddard Stark, believed that Robert, with his claim and charismatic personality, should be king and both stood aside.
\n
\nRobert was devastated by Lyanna\'s death, but was urged by Jon Arryn to marry Cersei of House Lannister, making an alliance with her father, Tywin Lannister, who had joined his cause late in the conflict and delivered the capital of King\'s Landing to him. He named Jon Arryn as his Hand while Eddard took his father\'s role as Warden of the North.
\n
\nStannis fought for Robert through the war. Stannis and Robert never loved one another. Despite Stannis\' service during the war, Robert made Renly the Lord of Storm\'s End following his victory. Renly was only a child during the civil war, so he did not fight.Stannis was made Lord of Dragonstone and served on his Robert\'s small council as Master of Ships. Renly later joined the small council as Master of Laws.
\n
\nRobert has been the King of the Andals and the First Men and the ruler of the Seven Kingdoms of Westeros since the end of the civil war. However, he is more concerned with drinking, whoring and hunting than with the minutiae of ruling his kingdom. He revels in the glory days of the rebellion. He leaves the running of the kingdom largely his small council, led by Jon Arryn. King Robert also loves to throw events such as tournaments at which he spares no expense. Unfortunately, after seventeen years this has left the realm deeply in debt, for a shocking six million Gold Dragons, half of that to House Lannister.  He apparently has three children with Cersei: Joffrey, Myrcella and Tommen. Unbeknownst to Robert all three were actually fathered by Cersei\'s twin brother Jaime Lannister. Robert has also fathered several illegitimate bastards. He has an unacknowledged bastard son named Gendry fathered on a tavern wench. He has an unacknowledged bastard daughter named Barra fathered on the prostitute Mhaegen.He has at least four other unacknowledged bastards fathered with various women in the city of King\'s Landing alone.
\n
\nJon Arryn began to investigate the lineage of Cersei\'s children, comparing their appearance to Robert\'s bastard offspring. He died under mysterious circumstances shortly after beginning his investigation. Robert has decided to ride north to Eddard\'s keep Winterfell to name him as Jon Arryn\'s replacement.</string>
    <string name="robb_stark">ROBB STARK</string>
    <string name="robb_text">"Robb is the eldest child of Lady Catelyn and Lord Eddard Stark. Eddard is the head of House Stark, Lord of Winterfell and Lord Paramount of the North, one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms. The Starks rule the region from their seat of Winterfell. Eddard is also the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.
\n
\nRobb was born at Riverrun and raised in Winterfell. His father left his mother the morning after their wedding to fight in Robert's Rebellion and did not return until after Robb was born. He has two younger trueborn brothers, Bran and Rickon, and two sisters, Sansa and Arya. He is also close to his bastard half-brother, Jon Snow, and to his father's ward, Theon Greyjoy, whom he counts as his best friend outside of the family. He has been trained from childhood to wield a sword and wear armor by Winterfell's Master-at-Arms Ser Rodrik Cassel, and is highly proficient with both for his young age. He lives at Winterfell with his family. "</string>
    <string name="samwell_tarly">SAMWELL TARLY</string>
    <string name="sam_text">"Samwell Tarly is the oldest son and former heir of Lord Randyll Tarly, the head of House Tarly and Lord of Horn Hill. House Tarly is one of the most powerful noble families in the Reach, and sworn to House Tyrell. By rights, Samwell would have grown up to be one of the top ranking lords of the Seven Kingdoms. However, his father Randyll Tarly is one of the most skilled military commanders in Westeros, and hoped for a son who would carry on his leadership of House Tarly in battle, not an overweight scholarly-minded son like Sam who has no thirst for violence. His father, ashamed of him, forced Samwell to take the black under threat of death in order to disinherit him. Had Sam refused to join the Night's Watch, his father bluntly told him that he would arrange a 'hunting trip' with his son in the woods, and then kill Sam in such a way that it looked like an accident. Sam departed for the Wall, leaving his younger brother as heir to House Tarly.
\n
\nSam was a virgin when he left for the Wall, and is a bit despondent about the restriction that his vows forbid him from ever taking a wife in the future. "</string>
    <string name="sandor_clegane">SANDOR CLEGANE</string>
    <string name="sandor_text">Sandor Clegane is a skilled warrior in the service of House Lannister, known primarily for the horrible facial scarring he bears on the right side of his face and for his fierce demeanor and lack of chivalry. Sandor is the younger brother of Ser Gregor Clegane, nicknamed \'the Mountain\', a monstrously huge knight and arguably the most feared man in Westeros. In his youth Gregor nearly burned off half of Sandor\'s face: Gregor found Sandor playing with a toy that Gregor had discarded, and without warning or uttering a word, Gregor grabbed Sandor and \'punished\' him by holding his head into a burning brazier. Gregor was only forced to stop after half a dozen servants managed to pry him away from his brother. The incident left severe burn scars over the right half of Sandor\'s face, thus he usually wears his hair long on that side to cover them. Ever since, Sandor has been deeply afraid of fire.
\nAlthough not as large as his older brother Gregor, Sandor is very large and an extremely formidable fighter in his own right, considered one of the most skilled and dangerous fighters in Westeros. Sandor gutted his first man in combat when he was twelve years old (given the date, this was probably as a young soldier during Robert\'s Rebellion). Sandor finds killing to be the best thing in the world, and although he isn\'t a crazed killer who will murder anyone regardless of the law like his brother, he cynically pursues occupations as a bodyguard and soldier which allow him to kill legally--though he scoffs at the hypocrisy of people who think there\'s really much of a difference. After seeing his brother knighted by Prince Rhaegar Targaryen despite being an infamously dishonorable man, Sandor became jaded with knighthood and developed an extreme contempt for romances and songs which present knights and wars as chivalrous and glorious, knowing all too well that supposedly honorable knights frequently butcher the innocent while claiming glory. Thus, Sandor has steadfastly refused to be knighted or take holy vows. Sandor wears a dark set of heavy armor when in battle, and is known to adorn a custom helmet shaped like a snarling hound\'s head befitting his nickname. He rides a personal warhorse called Stranger, whose namesake is the seventh and final god in the Faith of the Seven who represents death and the unknown.</string>
    <string name="sansa_stark">SANSA STARK</string>
    <string name="sansa_text">Sansa Stark is the eldest daughter and second child of Lady Catelyn and Lord Eddard Stark. Eddard is the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Stark is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Stark rules the region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also holds the titles of Lord of Winterfell and the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.
\n
\nSansa was born and raised at Winterfell. She has an older brother, Robb, two younger brothers, Bran and Rickon, a younger sister, Arya and a bastard half-brother, Jon. Sansa enjoys proper \'lady-like\' pursuits, and is good at sewing, embroidering, poetry, and music. She dreams of being a regal Queen like Cersei Lannister, and that just like in the epic songs she will meet her knight in shining armor. She has the Tully coloring as do most of her siblings, and Lady Catelyn thinks Sansa will be even more beautiful than she was when she was younger. She is often seen in contrast with her sister, Arya Stark who has neither her looks nor her accomplishments in feminine activities and comportment.</string>
    <string name="shae">SHAE</string>
    <string name="shae_text">Shae is a young woman of mystery, as she won\'t divulge her true origins. She has a Lorathi accent and is obviously not native to Westeros: she says she arrived there ten years ago. She is first encountered as a camp-follower with the Lannister army in the Riverlands. She has dreams of wealth and power, despite her low social status as a kept woman. She hails from the Free City of Lorath.
\n
\nAt unspecified points in the past, Shae has been to Dorne and Volantis.</string>
    <string name="stannis_baratheon">STANNIS BARATHEON</string>
    <string name="stannis_text">Stannis is the second born son of Steffon Baratheon and Cassana Baratheon, the younger brother of the late King Robert Baratheon and older brother of Renly Baratheon. Steffon was the head of House Baratheon and Lord Paramount of the Stormlands. The Stormlands are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Baratheon is one of the Great Houses of the realm. Steffon died when the boys were young and Robert inherited his titles. Stannis is a serious and severe man.
\n
\nRobert led a rebellion against King Aerys II Targaryen, deposing and replacing him as the ruler of the Seven Kingdoms. Stannis fought for Robert during the war. He was besieged at Storm\'s End for much of the conflict. He was rescued from starvation by the smuggler Davos, who brought a ship full of onions into the castle. Stannis knighted Davos as a reward but also punished him for his smuggling by cutting four finger tips from his right hand. Davos is fiercely loyal to Stannis and saw his punishment as just. Davos\'s son Matthos now serves Stannis as a scribe. Stannis went on to conquer Dragonstone, the seat of House Targaryen. During the Greyjoy Rebellion, Stannis destroyed the Greyjoy fleet.
\n
\nStannis and Robert never loved one another. Despite Stannis\' service during the war, Robert made Renly the Lord of Storm\'s End following his victory. Renly was only a child during the civil war, so he did not fight. Stannis was made Prince of Dragonstone and served on his brother\'s small council as Master of Ships. He is the least popular of the Baratheon brothers.
\n
\nHe married Selyse Florent. They have a loveless marriage; Stannis regards her as sickly and resents her failure to bear him a son. During the first season, Stannis is on Dragonstone for an extended stay, preferring the solitude of the island.
\n
\nHe has converted to the Lord of Light under the influence of the priestess Melisandre. His household have largely followed his conversion. He has adopted the flaming red heart of the Lord of Light with the stag of Baratheon in the middle as his sigil.</string>
    <string name="talisa_stark">TALISA STARK</string>
    <string name="talisa_text">Talisa was a noblewoman from the Free City of Volantis, the oldest and largest of the Free Cities.
\n
\nWhen Talisa was 12, her parents went to a wedding lasting several days, leaving her with her younger brother. The second day they were gone, it was the hottest day in Volantis, so she and her brother joined the other children to go for a swim in the River Rhoyne. While she was talking with a friend, she noticed that her brother was missing. Eventually, she found him floating face down in the water. Talisa and her friend pulled him to the shore but he was dead. Suddenly, a man with a tattoo of a fish on his face came and pushed her away. Had she reported him, it would have meant death for the slave to touch a noble. The slave kept on pushing on her brother\'s chest again and again until he was revived. As the slave cradled her brother and calmed him down, Talisa was inspired by the slave\'s selfless act. She decided two things right there and then: first, that when she came of age, she would not waste her years dancing with other nobles, and second that she would never live in a place where slavery was legal again. To this end, she sought and obtained medical training (rather than dancing with other nobles) and relocated to Westeros (slavery being outlawed in the Seven Kingdoms).</string>
    <string name="theon_greyjoy">THEON GREYJOY</string>
    <string name="theon_text">Theon is the youngest son of Lord Balon and Lady Alannys Greyjoy. Balon is the head of House Greyjoy and Lord of the Iron Islands. The Iron Islands are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Greyjoy is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Greyjoy rule the region from their seat at Pyke and Balon also holds the title Lord Reaper of Pyke.
\n
\nTheon was born at Pyke. He is Balon and Alannys\' fourth child after Rodrik, Maron, and Yara. Eight years before the start of the series Balon rose in rebellion against the Iron Throne. The ironborn were crushed in a war led by King Robert Baratheon and Lord Eddard Stark. Theon\'s brothers were both killed in the fighting. Balon surrendered and was allowed to remain Lord of the Iron Islands on the condition that Theon remain a hostage and ward of Eddard Stark. Theon\'s sister Yara remained on the Iron Islands. Despite his status as a hostage at Winterfell, Theon was been treated well by the Starks, and he and Robb Stark became best friends. Theon is a skilled archer. His cocky arrogance and cavalier actions contrast with the staid ways of the North.</string>
    <string name="tormund_">"TORMUND "</string>
    <string name="tormund_text">"Tormund is a trusted leader in his own right of a large warband of wildlings. He has joined his forces to those of King-Beyond-the-Wall Mance Rayder, and now functions as one of Mance's most trusted lieutenants.
\n
\nHe boasts of having bedded a she-bear, which he calls Shella. Ygritte insists that everyone knows he just made this story up. "</string>
    <string name="tyrion_lannister">TYRION LANNISTER</string>
    <string name="tyrion_text">"Tyrion Lannister is the youngest son of Joanna Lannister and Lord Tywin Lannister. Tywin is the head of House Lannister, the richest man in the Seven Kingdoms and Lord Paramount of the Westerlands. The Westerlands are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Lannister of Casterly Rock is one of the Great Houses of the realm. He is the younger brother of Jaime and Cersei Lannister. His mother Joanna Lannister died giving birth to him. His father and sister blame him for the death.
\n
\nHe is a dwarf, causing him problems and persecution. His size has led him to being referred to derisively by various names, such as 'the Imp' and 'The Halfman'. This is mitigated by his intellect and his family's wealth and power. Had an infant with dwarfism like Tyrion been born a commoner, he'd have simply been left out in the woods to die. However, Tyrion was born into a powerful noble House, and was therefore spared. Even though his father doesn't think much of him, he has had the benefits of being raised with wealth and education, and is expected to lead his life as a credit to the Lannister name. He is committed to the good of both his House and, since Cersei married King Robert Baratheon, his family's continued hold on the throne.
\n
\nWhen Tyrion was 16, he met a wheelwright's daughter named Tysha on the road, apparently the victim of an attempted rape. While his brother Jaime ran off the attackers, Tyrion helped Tysha recover from the ordeal, and they became lovers. They found a drunken, wandering septon willing to marry them and briefly, they lived as husband and wife. That is, until Lord Tywin learned what had happened. Jaime confessed that he organized the incident to make his brother happy, and Tysha was actually a prostitute. As a lesson, Tywin gave Tysha to his guards, paying her a silver coin for each man and forcing Tyrion to watch. By the end, there were so many silver coins that they were running out of her hands onto the ground. Tyrion has reciprocated Tywin's hatred ever since.
\n
\nHis two siblings have had positions of respect and responsibility since their teens. When Tyrion  turned sixteen (the age of manhood), Tywin Lannister put Tyrion in charge of the drains and cisterns at Casterly Rock. Tyrion brags that the sewage never flowed smoother to the sea.
\n
\nTyrion spends a lot of time at court in King's Landing to avoid his father. He gets on well with Jaime and his niece Myrcella and nephew Tommen, but has a colder relationship with Cersei and his sadistic nephew Joffrey. He has a fondness for prostitutes and drink, but is also intelligent, cunning, and educated. He also is a kind man who would protect the innocent claiming that he loves broken things. "</string>
    <string name="eddard_stark">EDDARD STARK</string>
    <string name="eddard_text">"Eddard Stark is the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Stark is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Stark rule the region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also holds the title Lord of Winterfell. In addition, he is the Warden of the North.
\n
\nEddard is married to Lady Catelyn of House Tully. Though they barely knew one another when they wed they have formed a strong and loving marriage. They have five legitimate children: Robb, Sansa, Arya, Bran and Rickon. Eddard also has an illegitimate bastard son, Jon Snow, reportedly by a common serving girl named Wylla. Jon's presence at Winterfell is a source of friction between Eddard and his wife.
\n
\nEddard is the second son of Lord Rickard Stark. Lord Rickard served King Aerys II Targaryen as Warden of the North. Eddard's older brother Brandon was Rickard's heir. Eddard also has a younger sister Lyanna and a younger brother Benjen. Eddard is a stoic, dutiful and honorable man and is considered to embody the values of the North.
\n
\nEddard is a trusted, close friend and counselor of King Robert Baratheon. He supported Robert's play for the throne by acting as a general in several major battles. Eddard's sister Lyanna, who was betrothed to Robert, was kidnapped by Prince Rhaegar Targaryen, sparking the war. Brandon protested the kidnapping but his attempt to bring Rhaegar to justice failed. Lord Rickard was summoned to court in King's Landing by Aerys and both Brandon and Rickard were executed by the Mad King. Their deaths left Eddard to inherit Rickard's responsibilities, serving King Robert instead. Brandon had been betrothed to Catelyn and Eddard also inherited his brother's bride. Lyanna died in Eddard's arms during the conflict. Eddard's other younger sibling, Benjen, still lives and is a member of the Night's Watch, an institution of which Eddard is a keen supporter. Eddard wields a Valyrian greatsword named Ice (an heirloom of House Stark) which he uses on ceremonial occasions. "</string>
    <string name="tywin_lannister">TYWIN LANNISTER</string>
    <string name="tywin_text">Tywin is the lord of House Lannister, the Lord Paramount of the Westerlands, and the richest man in the Seven Kingdoms. The Westerlands are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Lannister is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Lannister rule the region from their seat of Casterly Rock and Tywin also holds the title Lord of Casterly Rock. He is also the Warden of the West. He is a widower with three children, Jaime, Cersei and Tyrion. Casterly Rock, the Lannister\'s ancestral seat of power, is located over a group of highly productive goldmines, which have provided the Lannisters with immense wealth over the years and led to the speculation that Tywin \'shits gold.\'
\n
\nTywin is the son of Tytos Lannister. His father presided over a period of decline for the house, frittering away much of their fortune on poor investments and allowing himself to be mocked at court, creating a perception of weakness. Their vassals House Reyne of Castamere rebelled against Lord Tytos, and Tywin put down the rebellion personally, extinguishing their house and re-establishing the fearsome reputation of House Lannister. His ruthless destruction of House Reyne was immortalized in the song \'The Rains of Castamere\' and gave darker meaning to the common phrase \'A Lannister always pays his debts,\' which originally referred solely to the Lannister\'s vast fortune.
\n
\nTywin married his cousin Joanna Lannister and their first children were the fraternal twins Cersei and Jaime. She died after giving birth to Tyrion, which Tywin has blamed his son for ever since. When Jaime was diagnosed with a learning difficulty by a Maester who predicted that he would never read, Tywin sat with his son for four hours a day until he overcame his problems with transposing letters in his mind, much to Jaime\'s resentment.Tywin despises and hates his younger son, seeing him as misshapen and perverse. When Tyrion was very young, Jaime set him up with a prostitute. Jaime posed her as a common girl in distress that they rescued from bandits. Jaime chased the bandits off while Tyrion comforted the girl. They married, but when Tywin found out he was furious and made Jaime reveal the truth. Tywin paid her for every one of his guards to have sex with her and forced Tyrion to watch. Tywin\'s hatred of Tyrion has been reciprocated since. Nevertheless, all of Tywin\'s children are in awe of him and heed his counsel.
\n
\nTywin served as Hand of the King to Aerys II Targaryen for twenty years until the Mad King, driven by envy and distrust, rejected Tywin\'s proposal to marry his daughter Cersei to Prince Rhaegar and made his son Jaime a member of the Kingsguard. As members of the Kingsguard are forbidden to marry, Aerys had effectively robbed Tywin of his heir, which Tywin perceived as a great insult and resigned.During Robert\'s Rebellion Tywin remained neutral, answering neither the summons of the King nor the calls from the rebels, until the Battle of the Trident, after which it became clear that the rebels would win. Tywin marched with the full power of Casterly Rock to the capital, feigning that he had come to defend it from the rebellion. Aerys\' advisors urged the King not to trust Tywin, even Jaime Lannister, who knew his father would never back the losing side in a war.
\n
\nNevertheless, on Pycelle\'s advice, the gates were opened to the Lannister army. Tywin ordered the city to be taken and the royal family eliminated in a quick and efficient manner; as a result the city was sacked and the royal family massacred by Ser Gregor Clegane and Ser Amory Lorch. Upon seeing Tywin\'s betrayal, Aerys ordered Jaime to bring him Tywin\'s head and instructed the royal pyromancers to set King\'s Landing ablaze, to which Jaime responded by personally stabbing the Mad King in the back. When Robert Baratheon and Eddard Stark reached the Red Keep, Tywin presented the bodies of the royal family as proof of his allegiance. After the rebellion Robert Baratheon took the throne and married Tywin\'s daughter Cersei to cement the alliance between their houses.
\n
\nCersei gave birth to three children--Joffrey, Myrcella, and Tommen Baratheon. Unbeknownst to Tywin all three children are the product of her incestuous relationship with Jaime. This was discovered by both John Arryn and Eddard Stark, albeit independently, and bore the revelation that Joffrey--the oldest of the Baratheon children and the heir apparent to the Iron Throne--has no actual claim to rule. Tywin is close to his younger brother, Kevan who is his chief advisor, and Kevan\'s son Lancel was King Robert\'s squire, and many secretly believe Lancel gave Robert too much wine during his fatal hunt on Cersei\'s orders.</string>
    <string name="varys">VARYS</string>
    <string name="varys_text">Varys was born across the Narrow Sea in Lys. He was born a slave, and as a child he traveled with a troupe of actors all around the different Free Cities until a sorcerer in the city of Myr made an offer Varys\' master couldn\'t refuse. Varys was sold to the sorcerer, who gave him a potion that made him unable to move or speak but didn\'t dull his perceptions or sense of pain, and emasculated him (cutting off his testes and penis both) to use his sexual organs in a magical ritual, burning them in a brazier. Afterward the sorcerer had no use for Varys and threw him in the streets to die. Instead Varys resolved to live no matter what: begging, stealing, and selling the sexual use of what parts remained to him, doing anything to survive. He also became an excellent thief, but soon learned that stolen information was often a far more valuable commodity than any physical goods, and he worked his way up from the slums of Myr. He became a master spy and information trafficker, and his influence and reputation grew so great that he eventually found himself as a member of the small council in the Seven Kingdoms. His experience at the hands of the sorcerer had also left him with a bitter hatred for magic and its practitioners.
\n
\nAs a member of the King\'s small council, he serves as the Master of Whisperers, the King\'s foremost spymaster and intelligence agent. He holds no inherited title, castle or lands in Westeros, but is called \'Lord\' as a courtesy due to his position on the council, which traditionally is made up of high lords.
\n
\nVarys is bald and tends towards fat, due to his castration. He often puts on the public persona of being nothing more than a pudgy man well suited to the pleasantries of court life; humble, obsequious, fawning, and a little effeminate. This is simply a facade that Varys has developed, which often leads those who do not know him well to underestimate him as a cheerful and vapid flatterer. In reality he is a cunning and ruthless manipulator of court politics, on-par with Master of Coin Petyr \'Littlefinger\' Baelish, with whom he frequently spars. Unlike Baelish, Varys insists that his goals are to achieve what he honestly feels is best for the realm, though of course, what he and the current king feel is best might be two separate things.
\n
\nHe is disparagingly known as \'The Spider\' due to his vast web of intelligence sources. His sophisticated intelligence network - one of the largest in the world - spans both Westeros and Essos, as far as Vaes Dothrak and even Qarth. He refers to his agents and sources of information as his \'little birds\'. One of his jobs is to keep an eye on the movements of Viserys and Daenerys Targaryen and ensure they do not become a threat to King Robert\'s reign.</string>
    <string name="viserys_targaryen">VISERYS TARGARYEN</string>
    <string name="viserys_text">"Viserys is the second son and heir of King Aerys II Targaryen, the former ruler of the Seven Kingdoms. During Robert's Rebellion, after Viserys's older brother Rhaegar was killed at the Battle of the Trident, his father sent Viserys and his pregnant mother Queen Rhaella to safety on Dragonstone island, location of their family's ancestral castle. King Aerys was soon afterwards killed during the Sack of King's Landing, and thus at the age of only five Viserys became the titular head of the Targaryen dynasty, though by this point the rebellion was officially lost. Not long afterwards, his mother died in childbirth, while the forces of Robert Baratheon closed in on the island. Before they could arrive, Viserys and his baby sister Daenerys were smuggled to safety in the Free Cities, across the Narrow Sea on the continent of Essos. Bereft of followers, Viserys spent the next 17 years travelling between the Free Cities trying to find new supporters for an attempt to retake the Iron Throne. At times, however, he was left literally begging for food and shelter, much less an army.
\n
\nViserys claims the title of Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and refers to Robert Baratheon only as 'the Usurper'. After years spent fruitlessly wandering the Free Cities seeking military support to retake his throne, Viserys and Daenerys became guests of the powerful Magister Illyrio Mopatis of Pentos. "</string>
    <string name="ygritte">YGRITTE</string>
    <string name="ygritte_text">Ygritte was a quick-witted and courageous young spearwife. She had red hair and displayed great skill as an archer. Living north of the Wall, she was well skilled in survival and was staunchly loyal to the cause of Mance Rayder. She valued her status as a free woman, and disparaged those living south of the Wall as \'kneelers\', who blindly followed hereditary leaders instead of choosing a king.
\n
\nYgritte believed that because wildlings and Northerners both claim descent from the First Men, there is no need for them to be fighting, and that only the geographical divide of the Wall separates them. As with other wildlings, Ygritte understood that the real threat lies with the impending invasion of the White Walkers.</string>
    <string name="arya_text">Arya Stark is the youngest daughter and third child of Lady Catelyn and Lord Eddard Stark. Eddard is the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Stark is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Stark rules the region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also holds the title Lord of Winterfell. He is also the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.
\n
\nArya was born and raised at Winterfell. She has an older sister, Sansa Stark. She also has an older brother, Robb, two younger brothers, Bran and Rickon and a bastard half-brother, Jon Snow.
\n
\nArya rejects the notion that she must become a lady and marry for influence and power, feeling she can forge her own destiny. She is fascinated by warfare and training in the use of arms, and is bored by embroidery and other &amp;apos;lady-like&amp;apos; pursuits. She takes after her father and has a quarrelsome relationship with her sister Sansa. She is close to her half brother Jon who is also something of an outcast.</string>
    <string name="ellaria_sand">ELLARIA SAND</string>
    <string name="ellaia_text">&quot; Ellaria Sand is the paramour of Prince Oberyn Martell. She is the bastard daughter of Lord Harmen Uller, the Lord of Hellholt - thus she is one of the 'Sandy Dornishmen' of the central desert of Dorne, who possess particularly dark skin, burned brown by the hot desert sun. Her hair and eyes are also black.
\n
Ellaria is the mother of the four youngest of Oberyn's eight bastard daughters, who are all collectively known as the 'Sand Snakes'. Ellaria's four daughters with Oberyn are named Elia, Obella, Dorea, and Loreza Sand.
\n
She is described as not explicitly beautiful, as she is no longer a young woman and has borne four children, though still attractive and eye-catching, with an exotic, sensuous flair. Like her partner Oberyn, she expresses sexual interest in both women and men. It is not unusual for lords and ladies in Dorne to be openly bisexual, due to the relaxed attitude towards sexuality among the Dornish.
\n
Olenna Tyrell calls Ellaria 'The Serpent's  whore'. &quot;</string>
    <string name="alliser_header">ALLISER THORNE</string>
    <string name="alliser_text">"Ser Alliser Thorne is a member of the Night's Watch. He is from House Thorne, a noble house of the Crownlands sworn to the Iron Throne. During the time of the rebellion he protected and fought for House Targaryen but was eventually defeated. Tywin Lannister gave him the choice between death or the Night's Watch. Having no choice over the matter, Ser Alliser joined the Night's Watch leaving everything he had behind. After joining the Watch, he became a ranger. During the last winter, Thorne and his ranger companions were trapped in a massive winter storm and had to resort to cannibalism to survive. Later, Thorne became the master-of-arms at Castle Black and responsible for training the new recruits.
\n            Alliser Thorne is respected for his service to House Targaryen. During the Sack of King's Landing he fought on the walls of the city against the Lannister forces. After being defeated, he took the black and joined the Night's Watch, being given the choice of this or death; this is most likely the cause of Ser Alliser's animosity towards Jon Snow, as Jon's father Lord Eddard was a prominent leader in Robert's Rebellion which forced Thorne into exile at the Wall. In a notable change, in the TV series Thorne is an experienced ranger who has been beyond the Wall on several occasions while in the books he rarely leaves Castle Black. He's described as having eyes as black as onyx and black hair ridged with white.
\n
\nIt is Donal Noye the Blacksmith that tells Jon not to use his superior fighting skills to embarrass his fellow recruits. Jeor Mormont sends Ser Alliser to King's Landing with the severed hand of the animated corpse (it was still jumping and twitching), and he was ordered to lay it at Joffrey's feet. He thought that as a knight with old political allies in King's Landing Ser Alliser Thorne would be more respected and listened to, and they would see the danger the Night Watch was in and send aid. However, when he arrived and asked for an audience it was Tyrion Lannister who was in charge. Tyrion asked if the one waiting was Yoren, who had become his friend. Remembering Ser Alliser, he told them to give him a room where the rushes hadn't been changed in a while. It was weeks before he got an audience and by then the hand had rotted away. After his fruitless return, he is sent to Eastwatch-by-the-Sea rather than back to Castle Black.
\n
\nThorne, with Janos Slynt, returns to Castle Black much later than in the show, during the Battle of Castle Black. Their presence proves to be a hindrance rather than assistance: they seize command on the castle and interrogate Jon roughly. They accuse him of oathbreaking, cowardice, and desertion. Maester Aemon assures them that Jon has already explained his deeds to him and Donal Noye, but they either don't believe or don't care. Jon repeats what he told before, that he was acting at Qhorin's orders, but his explanations are rejected. Thorne, who always loathed Jon, accuses him of murdering Qhorin, suggesting that he is in league with those who murdered Mormont, and that Benjen Stark may have a hand in all of that. Slynt teases Jon by claiming that Eddard Stark died a traitor. Hearing the lies about his father, Jon's patience runs out. When Thorne grabs his arm, he yanks free and grabs Thorne by the throat with such ferocity that he lifts him off the floor. The Eastwatch men pulls Jon off Thorne and he is locked in an ice cell. Four days later, he is released. Thorne and Slynt order Jon to go to the Wildling camp to parley with Mance Rayder, but actually his mission is to kill Mance. Jon knows well that the Wildlings will probably kill him on the spot, but he has no other choice but to do as is told, knowing that a refusal will confirm the false accusations against him and give Thorne and Slynt an excuse to kill him.
\n
\nAfter the battle is over, Thorne continues naming Jon a turncloak. He claims that Jon failed to kill Mance Rayder because he was in league with him, but few believe that. "</string>
    <string name="barristan_selmy">BARRISTAN SELMY</string>
    <string name="barristan_text">Ser Barristan Selmy is the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard, the elite bodyguard of the King of the Andals and the First Men. Barristan is the only known member of House Selmy, a minor house that serves House Baratheon. Barristan Selmy is noted as an extremely capable warrior, even in his old age, and has a reputation for honor and chivalry that is second to none. He served in the Kingsguard of Aerys II Targaryen. He fought in the battle against the Kingswood Brotherhood and slew their leader Simon Toyne. Jaime Lannister, then aged 16, squired for Selmy during the battle and greatly admired his skill.
\nHe never wavered in his loyalty to House Targaryen during Robert&amp;apos;s Rebellion, in accordance with the vows he swore when he joined the Kingsguard. Both Robert Baratheon and Ned Stark held Ser Barristan in very high esteem. Upon assuming the throne, Robert pardoned him and made him Lord Commander of the Kingsguard</string>
    <string name="benjen_stark">BENJEN STARK</string>
    <string name="benjen_text">Benjen Stark is the youngest son of Lord Rickard Stark. Rickard was the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Stark is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Stark rule the region from their seat of Winterfell and Rickard also held the title Lord of Winterfell.
\n
\nBenjen is the younger brother of Brandon, Eddard and Lyanna. Rickard, Brandon and Lyanna were all killed in the civil war known as Robert\'s Rebellion. Eddard inherited his father\'s titles and responsibilities.
\n
\nBenjen joined the Night\'s Watch, the military force which patrols the Wall and guards the northern border of the Seven Kingdoms. He earned the rank of First Ranger. Benjen is a hero to Eddard\'s bastard son Jon Snow.</string>
    <string name="craster">CRASTER</string>
    <string name="craster_text">&quot;Craster is a wildling who lives north of the Wall. He lives in a fortified homestead, rather grandly called Craster's Keep, along with his daughters and wives. When his daughters grow old enough he marries them, and then incestuously fathers new children with them. At the time of the War of the Five Kings, he has nineteen wives. He is counted as an ally of the Night's Watch and allows his keep to be used as a redoubt by the Watch on their rangings northwards. However, he is also regarded as an unsavory character and his relationship with his daughters is regarded as sordid. The Night's Watch grudgingly has to tolerate this, as he is one of their few sources of information and shelter beyond the Wall. &quot;</string>
    <string name="daario_naharis">DAARIO NAHARIS</string>
    <string name="daario_text">Daario is a Tyroshi sellsword, employed as a lieutenant in the Second Sons. He is apparently held in high enough regard by the company\'s co-captains, Mero and Prendahl na Ghezn, that they allow him to join them in contract negotiations and discussions of the company\'s future.
\n
\nHis weapons-of-choice are a stiletto and an arakh, with custom-made hilts in the shape of beautiful, naked women.</string>
    <string name="greyworm">GREY WORM</string>
    <string name="grey_text">Grey Worm was originally a boy taken into slavery by the Good Masters of Astapor, an oligarchy of slave-traders dedicated to the training and commerce of Unsullied, warrior-eunuch slaves trained into absolute obedience since early childhood. It later is revealed that he is originally from the Summer Islands and was taken by the slavers in a raid as a baby. He has no memory of his life before being an Unsullied.
\n
\nHe is released from slavery after Daenerys Targaryen buys all the Unsullied in the city and has them put all slave owners in Astapor to the sword and release all slaves. Once released, Grey Worm, like all his brethren, chooses to fight for Daenerys as a free man.</string>
    <string name="hodor">HODOR</string>
    <string name="hodor_text">Hodor is simple-minded (i.e. mentally disabled) and he is only capable of saying one word, \'hodor\' (which is a nonsense word), though he can apparently understand complex instructions other people give him. Nonetheless, House Stark set him to work at a productive occupation within his capacities, as a stableboy serving at Winterfell. Hodor is incredibly large and strong. While he is slow of wits, he is gentle and loyal to the Starks. He is actually Old Nan\'s great-grandson and only living relative.</string>
    <string name="ilyn_payne">ILYN PAYNE</string>
    <string name="ilyn_text">Ser Ilyn Payne had his tongue removed on the order of the Mad King for suggesting that Tywin Lannister, then Hand of the King and whom Ser Ilyn served as Captain of the Guards, was the true ruler of Westeros rather than King Aerys II. He served Robert Baratheon as \'the King\'s Justice\' - the royal executioner.</string>
    <string name="janos_slynt">JANOS SLYNT</string>
    <string name="janos_text">Janos Slynt is the commander of the King\'s Landing City Watch (also called the \'Gold Cloaks\'), with almost two thousand men under his command. He is charged with keeping peace and order in the city and quelling unrest. 
\n           He was a commoner, a butcher\'s son, who joined the City Watch and rose through the ranks first to captain of the Iron Gate and then to become its commander at the death of the former commander, Manly Stokeworth. The City Watch or Gold Cloaks is one of the few institutions in Westeros to permit promotion of non-nobles from the ranks. He is a somewhat humorless man who is arrogant and proud of his achievements. He is bald, stout, and heavily jowled, often described as frog faced and shaped like a keg. He is the father of Morros, Jothos, Danos, and a daughter.</string>
    <string name="jaqen_h_ghar">JAQEN H\'GHAR</string>
    <string name="jaqen_text">"Jaqen is surprisingly calm in the face of danger, yet courteous. He uses an odd speech pattern in which he refers to both himself and others using the third person indefinite, e.g. saying 'a man thanks a girl' when he is directly addressing Arya and expressing his own thanks. 
\n            Jaqen H'ghar is a mysterious man - introducing himself as a Lorathi criminal - who was arrested and put in the dungeons of King's Landing, before being recruited by Yoren to join the Night's Watch. He is in Yoren's party as the latter smuggles Arya Stark out of King's Landing. He travels with them to the lands south of Harrenhal, where they are captured by Lannister forces.
\n
\nIn reality, 'Jaqen H'ghar' is just an assumed identity of one of the Faceless Men of Braavos, a feared order of mysterious assassins with the ability to change their appearance at will. After the Jaqen persona is of no more use to him, the Faceless Man shapeshifts into a new appearance. "</string>
    <string name="lysa_arryn">LYSA ARRYN</string>
    <string name="mance_rayder">MANCE RAYDER</string>
    <string name="mance_text">Mance Rayder was once a noted ranger of the Night\'s Watch. He was actually born a wildling and is proud that he has wildling blood in his veins, but as an infant he was left at one of the castles on the Wall to be raised in the Night\'s Watch.
\n
\nAs a young man, he deserted his post and fled north of the Wall to join the wildlings.He rose to become the King-Beyond-the-Wall, a title bestowed on a wildling leader who manages to unify all of the tribes under his command. It appears he has held the position of King-Beyond-the-Wall for more than a decade, as Ser Alliser Thorne mentions he was King-Beyond-the-Wall during the previous winter.</string>
    <string name="missandei">MISSANDEI</string>
    <string name="missandei_text">"Missandei is a slave, born on the island of Naath in the Summer Sea, off the coast of the continent of Sothoryos. She was enslaved at a young age and eventually was put to work as a translator for the slaver-master Kraznys mo Nakloz, one of the Good Masters of Astapor.
\n
\nMissandei speaks nineteen languages including High Valyrian (her favorite), the Low Valyrian dialect of Slaver's Bay, Dothraki, the Common Tongue of Westeros, and has some knowledge of the functionally dead language of the Ghiscari Empire.
\nMissandei was freed when Daenerys Targaryen took the Unsullied army and used it to overthrow the slavers. Missandei now serves Daenerys as her trusted handmaiden. "</string>
    <string name="oberyn_martell">OBERYN MARTELL</string>
    <string name="oberyn_text">Prince Oberyn is the younger brother of Prince Doran Martell and Princess Elia Martell; like most members of House Martell, he is styled \'Prince\' instead of \'Lord\'. He is nicknamed \'the Red Viper\' for his knowledge of poisons and for his unusual, deadly style of combat. Oberyn is known for being an accomplished warrior, but Tyrion implies that he is just as infamous for his sexual appetite. Oberyn\'s official paramour is Ellaria Sand; she is his wife in all but name.
\n             He has eight acknowledged bastard daughters, the last four born to Ellaria Sand, all of whom he has loving relationships with. He named the fifth one, Elia Sand, after his late sister.
\n
\nWhen he was a teenager, Oberyn was accompianed by his little sister Elia on a visit to Casterly Rock. While there, Oberyn and Elia were eager to see the \'monster\' that had just been born. Cersei finally showed them Tyrion, but the Martell siblings were somewhat disappointed to see that he was just a baby, and somewhat disturbed by Cersei\'s already strong hatred of him.
\n
\nPrince Oberyn trained at the Citadel in his youth, in order to become a maester. Although he ultimately abandoned his studies, he became well versed in the use of poisons in the process.
\n
\nOberyn also travelled to Essos in his youth and saw the Unsulied in Astapor, who he states are impressive on the battlefield, but less in the bedroom. He lived there for a total of five years.</string>
    <string name="olenna_tyrell">OLENNA TYRELL</string>
    <string name="olenna_text">Olenna Tyrell is the widow of Lord Luthor Tyrell and the mother of Mace Tyrell, the current Lord of Highgarden, Warden of the South, Lord Paramount of the Reach, and head of House Tyrell. She is the grandmother of his children Loras and Margaery. She was born into House Redwyne, one of the most prominent and powerful vassals of House Tyrell.
\n
\nIn her youth, Olenna was engaged to a member of House Targaryen, as it was \'all the rage\' at the time; it was her sister Viola whom Luthor Tyrell was expected to marry. The night before Luthor was to propose to Viola, Olenna snuck into his chamber and seduced him; the thought of marrying a Targaryen and his \'ludicrous silver hair\' did not appeal to her.
\n
\nAlthough Olenna consistently referred to Luthor as an oaf, she was genuinely fond of him, and confided to Margaery that she had some difficulty accepting his death after his body was delivered to her.</string>
    <string name="osha">OSHA</string>
    <string name="osha_text">Osha is a wildling spearwife, one of the \'Free Folk\' who live north of the Wall. Like other wildlings, she worships the Old Gods of the Forest. Due to the rising threat of the White Walkers and their undead wights, Osha fled south of the Wall with a group of other wildlings, hoping to go \'as far south as south goes\'. They bypassed the wall by taking a boat across the Bay of Seals, to the east of the Wall.</string>
    <string name="podrick_payne">PODRICK PAYNE</string>
    <string name="podrick_text">"Podrick Payne is a distant cousin of the more famous Ser Ilyn Payne, the King's Justice, and member of a lesser branch of House Payne. He has been made a squire to Tyrion Lannister, and hopes to one day complete his training and become a knight. "</string>
    <string name="maester_pycelle">MAESTER PYCELLE</string>
    <string name="pycelle_text">"Pycelle has been Grand Maester of the Seven Kingdoms for decades and has served under four kings when the series begins. The Grand Maester is the King's personal maester, a learned man wise in history, science and medicine who also provides counsel. The Grand Maester sits on the King's small council, which runs the realm in the name of the King. He served King Aerys II Targaryen prior to Robert's Rebellion. He remembers Aerys as a great man before his descent into madness. When Tywin Lannister marched to the gates of King's Landing following the rebel victory at the Battle of the Trident and all of the King's advisors told Aerys not to trust the Lord of Casterly Rock, Pycelle gave the opposite counsel and the city gates were opened, allowing the Lannister forces to sack the capital.
\n
\nFollowing the rebellion he remained Grand Maester to King Robert Baratheon. He is joined on the small council by the Master of Coin Petyr Baelish, also called Littlefinger, the Master of Whisperers Varys, the Master of Ships Stannis Baratheon and the Master of Laws Renly Baratheon. He plays up his age to appear harmless but is actually mentally sharp and dangerous. He is loyal to Queen Cersei Lannister and was involved in the birth of all of her children, assisted by midwives. Pycelle also privately flouts the vow of celibacy taken by maesters, as he enjoys the company of prostitutes such as Ros. "</string>
    <string name="renly_baratheon">RENLY BARATHEON</string>
    <string name="renly_text">Renly is the third and youngest son of Steffon Baratheon and Cassana Baratheon. Steffon was the head of House Baratheon and Lord Paramount of the Stormlands. The Stormlands are one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Baratheon is one of the Great Houses of the realm. Renly has two older brothers Robert and Stannis. Steffon died when the boys were young and Robert inherited his titles. Robert led a rebellion against King Aerys II Targaryen, deposing and replacing him as the King on the Iron Throne. He made Renly the Lord of Storm\'s End following his victory. Renly was only a child during the civil war, so he did not fight.
\n
\nRenly serves Robert as Master of Laws on the King\'s small council in King\'s Landing. He is fourth in line to the throne, behind his nephews Joffrey and Tommen and his older brother Stannis. Renly is popular at court because of his friendly manner and keen fashion sense.
\n
\nBy the time the TV series begins, Renly has been involved in a homosexual romance with Ser Loras Tyrell for many years. They must keep their love a secret, because the dominant religion of the realm, the Faith of the Seven, considers homosexuality to be a sin.</string>
    <string name="rickon_stark">RICKON STARK</string>
    <string name="rickon_text">Rickon is the fifth child and youngest son of Lady Catelyn and Lord Eddard Stark. Eddard is the head of House Stark and Lord Paramount of the North. The North is one of the constituent regions of the Seven Kingdoms and House Stark is one of the Great Houses of the realm. House Stark rule the region from their seat of Winterfell and Eddard also holds the title Lord of Winterfell. He is also the Warden of the North to King Robert Baratheon.
\n
\nRickon was born and raised at Winterfell. He has two older brothers Robb and Bran and two older sisters Sansa and Arya. He also has an older bastard half-brother of Jon Snow. He is named for his grandfather, Rickard, who died eleven years before Rickon was born. He is six when the TV series begins</string>
    <string name="robin_arryn">ROBIN ARRYN</string>
    <string name="robin_text">Robin was born in King\'s Landing where his father was serving as the Hand of the King for Robert Baratheon. Jon begins an investigation into Robert\'s legitimate and bastard children and then takes a fever and dies suddenly. Robin inherits Jon\'s position. Lysa rushes Robin back to the Eyrie following Jon\'s death. She writes to her sister to accuse House Lannister of poisoning Jon. Lysa was fiercely protective of Robin and he leads an extremely sheltered life.</string>
    <string name="roose_bolton">ROOSE BOLTON</string>
    <string name="roose_text">Roose Bolton is the head of House Bolton, a vassal family to House Stark of Winterfell. He is the Lord of the Dreadfort. Roose takes pride in his house sigil; the flayed man. Although torture is outlawed in the North, his family is famous for flaying the skin from their enemies as a means of torture and execution. Roose fought for Lord Eddard Stark in the civil war known as Robert\'s Rebellion and proved his worth as a soldier in the Battle of the Trident.
\n
\nRoose Bolton had a trueborn son, Domeric, who perished, forcing Roose to rely on his bastard son, Ramsay Snow.</string>
    <string name="salladhor_saan">SALLADHOR SAAN</string>
    <string name="salladhor_text">"Salladhor Saan is a pirate-lord from Lys, though a native of the Summer Isles. He commands a fleet of thirty ships that frequently prey on merchant ships traveling between Westeros and the Free Cities to the east. Sometimes in pursuit of extra wealth, he shifts from pure piracy to being a sellsail: hiring out the services of his ships and crews to the highest bidder, to act as mercenaries in various conflicts. 
\n            He was recruited to King Stannis Baratheon's cause but Salladhor abandoned him after the Battle of the Blackwater. Salladhor re-entered Stannis' service, however, after Stannis secured a loan from the Iron Bank of Braavos, enabling him to pay Salladhor's fee. "</string>
    <string name="shireen_baratheon">SHIREEN BARATHEON</string>
    <string name="shireen_text">&quot;Shireen is the daughter of Stannis and Selyse Baratheon. Her father is the head of House Baratheon of Dragonstone and has declared himself King on the Iron Throne. Shireen is Stannis's only living child and therefore his heir presumptive. She is the same age as Arya Stark. She had three older brothers, who were stillborn.
\n
The left side of her face is scarred by Greyscale.
\n
Shireen was not born a princess, but was born into a powerful noble family. She only recently became a princess, after her father declared himself king upon her uncle King Robert&amp;apos;s death. &quot;</string>
    <string name="tommen_baratheon">TOMMEN BARATHEON</string>
    <string name="tommen_text">&quot;Tommen is presented as the youngest son of King Robert Baratheon and Queen Cersei Lannister. Cersei and Robert made a political marriage alliance after Robert took the throne by force from the Mad King Aerys II Targaryen. Tommen's real father is Jaime Lannister, his mother's twin brother. He has an older brother,
\n
Joffrey, and an older sister Myrcella with the same obfuscated parentage. Tommen is good-natured and passive in contrast to his brother Joffrey, who sometimes bullied Tommen for amusement. Like his sister, he is fond of his uncle Tyrion. As he is not old enough to rule in his own right and command the military forces of the Seven Kingdoms, he does not yet bear the title of Protector of the Realm. &quot;</string>
    <string name="xaro_xhoan_daxos">XARO XHOAN DAXOS</string>
    <string name="xaro_text">Xaro Xhoan Daxos is a powerful merchant prince of the great city of Qarth born on the Summer Islands, located far to the south of the Dothraki sea, beyond the Red Waste. He is a member of the Thirteen, an organization that rules over Qarth.
\n
\nHe boasts of being the wealthiest man in Qarth. In Qarth, a merchant invited into the Thirteen remains in his seat for as long as he is feared or respected enough not to be denied membership by his other twelve peers.</string>

</resources>
